RANJAN MAITRA

Full Stack Software Developer

Phone 703-953-8413

Email rj.maitra@gmail.com

Portfolio rj-maitra.github.io
GitHub github.com/rj-maitra
LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ranjanmaitra

Technical Skills

Full-Stack Languages

- Python
- C#/.NET
- MERN (React JavaScript)

Databases & Formats

- SQL (MySQL, SQLite)
- NoSQL (MongoDB)
- JSON, BSON
- APIs
- LINQ Querying

Front-End UI and UX

- HTMI 5
- CSS 3
- LESS
- SASS
- JavaScript ES5, ES6
- AJAX
- Jinja
- jQuery
- Bootstrap

Frameworks

- Flask MVC
- Django MVC
- Entity ORM
- ASP.NET Core
- Express.js
- Node.js
- EJS Templating Engine

Software

- Git Version Control
- Visual Studio Code
- MySQL Workbench
- · Mongoose Server
- MAMP Server
- Session
- Bcrypt
- Microsoft Office Suite
- SEI Trust Accounting Platform

Methodologies

- CRUD Operations
- MVC Frameworks
- OOP (Object-Oriented Programming)
- ERD (Entity Relationship Diagrams)
- REST-ful Architecture
- Big-O Notation

Deployment

- Amazon EC2
- NGINX
- Gunicorn

Professional Summary

Intelligent, thoughtful banker-turned-coder entering the tech industry as a Software Developer. Experienced in creating full-stack applications in Python, C#, and MERN, from user experience design to implementing object-oriented programming, building databases, deploying applications, and solving algorithms. Over 4 years' experience working Fiduciary in financial services at a Fortune 500 company.

Key Projects

Yelp 2.0 — MERN using React JavaScript

A simple restaurant reviewer in which visitors may add restaurants and reviews. Others may add reviews to existing restaurants. Features include restaurants sorted by average rating, entry validation, and the prevention of duplicate restaurants in the database.

Activity Planner — C# using ASP.NET Core

An activity planner in which registered users may plan fun activities and join other user-created activities. Features login and password validations, Bcrypt password hashing, Session, and one-to-many and many-to-many schema relationships.

<u>Travel Buddy</u> — Python using Django MVC Framework

A travel organizer allowing registered users to coordinate travel plans and join travel itineraries created by others. Featuring login validations, Bcrypt password hashing, Session, and various schema relationships.

Employment

Driver, Uber & Lyft 2016—2019

2012-2016

2012-2012

Trust Distribution Specialist II

Bank of New York Mellon Wealth Management — Pittsburgh, PA

Processed terminating Fiduciary and Estate trusts and facilitated distribution in accordance with governing instruments while working in a highly-confidential, compartmentalized environment.

- Provided centralized support to interested parties internally and externally throughout the distribution process
- Prepared detailed trust overviews and distribution proposals for Fiduciary Committee approval
- Handled 100+ accounts over target workload of 60 with an error rate of 1.5% (below target 6%)
- Utilized extensive Excel macros to create comprehensive asset allocation and cash distribution schedules for beneficiaries
- Trained 7 team members on identifying and analyzing accrued undistributed income due to decedent's estate

Account Open/Distribution Unit Internship

Bank of New York Mellon Wealth Management — Pittsburgh, PA

3-month internship performing various entry-level tasks between two departments

- Logged coding changes for account maintenance and large-volume wire projects
- Retrieved, logged, and prepared account vault work documentation for two departments
- Reviewed and prepared new accounts, and distributed terminating IMA, IRA, and Trustee accounts to specialists for processing

Education

Full-Stack Software Developer Program, Coding Dojo, 2019 — Tysons Corner, VA

14-week immersive with 1,200+ hours of coding experience, Triple Black Belt recipient (>99% overall)

- Learned Python, C#/.NET, and MERN (React) language stacks
- Developed and deployed web applications with complete front- and back-ends
- Engineered OOP methodology, REST-ful routes, CRUD operations, API integration, relational (SQL) and non-relational (NoSQL) databases
- Solved algorithms and data structures, including: Arrays, loops, dictionaries, stacks, queues, linked lists, recursion, heaps, binary trees, tries, and graphs

B.S. Finance, Rochester Institute of Technology, 2012 — Rochester, NY

Concentration: Sociology and Anthropology

- DVRS of Virginia Scholarship
- Merit Scholarship

- Presidential and Dean Scholarship
- Achievement Scholarship

Select Community Activities

Assisted Make-A-Wish Grapevine Fundraiser with event coordination and auction setup, 2014-2015 Co-presented Diversity and Inclusion Presentation to BNY Mellon AMSS Dept., 2013 Assisted The Pittsburgh Food Bank with intake and distribution of donated items, 2012 Co-developed and proposed an improved data algorithm to FoodLink, 2012 Founding Member of RIT's Sigma Nu Fraternity (Mu Zeta Chapter), 2010-2011